Rewrite (or analyze) repository history

    git-filter-repo destructively rewrites history (unless --analyze or
    --dry-run are given) according to specified rules.  It refuses to do any
    rewriting unless either run from a clean fresh clone, or --force was
    given.

    Basic Usage:
      git-filter-repo --analyze
      git-filter-repo [FILTER/RENAME/CONTROL OPTIONS]

    See EXAMPLES section for details.

Analysis:
  --analyze             Analyze repository history and create a report that
                        may be useful in determining what to filter in a
                        subsequent run. Will not modify your repo.
  --report-dir DIR_OR_FILE
                        Directory to write report, defaults to
                        GIT_DIR/filter_repo/analysis,refuses to run if exists,
                        --force delete existing dir first.

Filtering based on paths (see also --filename-callback):
  These options specify the paths to select.  Note that much like git
  itself, renames are NOT followed so you may need to specify multiple
  paths, e.g. `--path olddir/ --path newdir/`

  --invert-paths        Invert the selection of files from the specified
                        --path-{match,glob,regex} options below, i.e. only
                        select files matching none of those options.
  --path-match, --path DIR_OR_FILE
                        Exact paths (files or directories) to include in
                        filtered history. Multiple --path options can be
                        specified to get a union of paths.
  --path-glob GLOB      Glob of paths to include in filtered history. Multiple
                        --path-glob options can be specified to get a union of
                        paths.
  --path-regex REGEX    Regex of paths to include in filtered history.
                        Multiple --path-regex options can be specified to get
                        a union of paths
  --use-base-name       Match on file base name instead of full path from the
                        top of the repo. Incompatible with --path-rename, and
                        incompatible with matching against directory names.

Renaming based on paths (see also --filename-callback):
  --path-rename, --path-rename-match OLD_NAME:NEW_NAME
                        Path to rename; if filename or directory matches
                        OLD_NAME rename to NEW_NAME. Multiple --path-rename
                        options can be specified. NOTE: If you combine
                        filtering options with renaming ones, do not rely on a
                        rename argument to select paths; you also need a
                        filter to select them.

Path shortcuts:
  --paths-from-file FILENAME
                        Specify several path filtering and renaming
                        directives, one per line. Lines with '==>' in them
                        specify path renames, and lines can begin with
                        'literal:' (the default), 'glob:', or 'regex:' to
                        specify different matching styles. Blank lines and
                        lines starting with a '#' are ignored.
  --subdirectory-filter DIRECTORY
                        Only look at history that touches the given
                        subdirectory and treat that directory as the project
                        root. Equivalent to using '--path DIRECTORY/ --path-
                        rename DIRECTORY/:'
  --to-subdirectory-filter DIRECTORY
                        Treat the project root as if it were under DIRECTORY.
                        Equivalent to using '--path-rename :DIRECTORY/'

Content editing filters (see also --blob-callback):
  --replace-text EXPRESSIONS_FILE
                        A file with expressions that, if found, will be
                        replaced. By default, each expression is treated as
                        literal text, but 'regex:' and 'glob:' prefixes are
                        supported. You can end the line with '==>' and some
                        replacement text to choose a replacement choice other
                        than the default of '***REMOVED***'.
  --strip-blobs-bigger-than SIZE
                        Strip blobs (files) bigger than specified size (e.g.
                        '5M', '2G', etc)
  --strip-blobs-with-ids BLOB-ID-FILENAME
                        Read git object ids from each line of the given file,
                        and strip all of them from history

Renaming of refs (see also --refname-callback):
  --tag-rename OLD:NEW  Rename tags starting with OLD to start with NEW. For
                        example, --tag-rename foo:bar will rename tag
                        foo-1.2.3 to bar-1.2.3; either OLD or NEW can be
                        empty.

Filtering of commit messages (see also --message-callback):
  --replace-message EXPRESSIONS_FILE
                        A file with expressions that, if found in commit or
                        tag messages, will be replaced. This file uses the
                        same syntax as --replace-text.
  --preserve-commit-hashes
                        By default, since commits are rewritten and thus gain
                        new hashes, references to old commit hashes in commit
                        messages are replaced with new commit hashes
                        (abbreviated to the same length as the old reference).
                        Use this flag to turn off updating commit hashes in
                        commit messages.
  --preserve-commit-encoding
                        Do not reencode commit messages into UTF-8. By
                        default, if the commit object specifies an encoding
                        for the commit message, the message is re-encoded into
                        UTF-8.

Filtering of names & emails (see also --name-callback and --email-callback):
  --mailmap FILENAME    Use specified mailmap file (see git-shortlog(1) for
                        details on the format) when rewriting author,
                        committer, and tagger names and emails. If the
                        specified file is part of git history, historical
                        versions of the file will be ignored; only the current
                        contents are consulted.
  --use-mailmap         Same as: '--mailmap .mailmap'

Parent rewriting:
  --replace-refs {delete-no-add,delete-and-add,update-no-add,update-or-add,update-and-add,old-default}
                        How to handle replace refs (see git-replace(1)).
                        Replace refs can be added during the history rewrite
                        as a way to allow users to pass old commit IDs (from
                        before git-filter-repo was run) to git commands and
                        have git know how to translate those old commit IDs to
                        the new (post-rewrite) commit IDs. Also, replace refs
                        that existed before the rewrite can either be deleted
                        or updated. The choices to pass to --replace-refs thus
                        need to specify both what to do with existing refs and
                        what to do with commit rewrites. Thus 'update-and-add'
                        means to update existing replace refs, and for any
                        commit rewrite (even if already pointed at by a
                        replace ref) add a new refs/replace/ reference to map
                        from the old commit ID to the new commit ID. The
                        default is update-no-add, meaning update existing
                        replace refs but do not add any new ones. There is
                        also a special 'old-default' option for picking the
                        default used in versions prior to git-filter-
                        repo-2.45, namely 'update-and-add' upon the first run
                        of git-filter-repo in a repository and 'update-or-add'
                        if running git-filter-repo again on a repository.
  --prune-empty {always,auto,never}
                        Whether to prune empty commits. 'auto' (the default)
                        means only prune commits which become empty (not
                        commits which were empty in the original repo, unless
                        their parent was pruned). When the parent of a commit
                        is pruned, the first non-pruned ancestor becomes the
                        new parent.
  --prune-degenerate {always,auto,never}
                        Since merge commits are needed for history topology,
                        they are typically exempt from pruning. However, they
                        can become degenerate with the pruning of other
                        commits (having fewer than two parents, having one
                        commit serve as both parents, or having one parent as
                        the ancestor of the other.) If such merge commits have
                        no file changes, they can be pruned. The default
                        ('auto') is to only prune empty merge commits which
                        become degenerate (not which started as such).
  --no-ff               Even if the first parent is or becomes an ancestor of
                        another parent, do not prune it. This modifies how
                        --prune-degenerate behaves, and may be useful in
                        projects who always use merge --no-ff.

Generic callback code snippets:
  --filename-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing filenames; see
                        CALLBACKS sections below.
  --file-info-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing file and metadata; see
                        CALLBACKS sections below.
  --message-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing messages (both commit
                        messages and tag messages); see CALLBACKS section
                        below.
  --name-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing names of people; see
                        CALLBACKS section below.
  --email-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing emails addresses; see
                        CALLBACKS section below.
  --refname-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing refnames; see
                        CALLBACKS section below.
  --blob-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing blob objects; see
                        CALLBACKS section below.
  --commit-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing commit objects; see
                        CALLBACKS section below.
  --tag-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing tag objects. Note that
                        lightweight tags have no tag object and are thus not
                        handled by this callback. See CALLBACKS section below.
  --reset-callback FUNCTION_BODY_OR_FILE
                        Python code body for processing reset objects; see
                        CALLBACKS section below.

Sensitive Data Removal Handling:
  --sensitive-data-removal, --sdr
                        This rewrite is intended to remove sensitive data from
                        a repository. Gather extra information from the
                        rewrite needed to provide additional instructions on
                        how to clean up other copies.
  --no-fetch            By default, --sensitive-data-removal will trigger a
                        mirror-like fetch of all refs from origin, discarding
                        local changes, but ensuring that _all_ fetchable refs
                        that hold on to the sensitve data are rewritten. This
                        flag removes that fetch, risking that other refs
                        continue holding on to the sensitive data. This option
                        is implied by --partial or any flag that implies
                        --partial.

Location to filter from/to:
  Specifying alternate source or target locations implies --partial,
  except that the normal default for --replace-refs is used.  However,
  unlike normal uses of --partial, this doesn't risk mixing old and new
  history since the old and new histories are in different repositories.

  --source SOURCE       Git repository to read from
  --target TARGET       Git repository to overwrite with filtered history

Ordering of commits:
  --date-order          Processes commits in commit timestamp order.

Miscellaneous options:
  --help, -h            Show this help message and exit.
  --version             Display filter-repo's version and exit.
  --proceed             Avoid triggering the no-arguments-specified check.
  --force, -f           Rewrite repository history even if the current repo
                        does not look like a fresh clone. History rewriting is
                        irreversible (and includes immediate pruning of
                        reflogs and old objects), so be cautious about using
                        this flag.
  --partial             Do a partial history rewrite, resulting in the mixture
                        of old and new history. This disables rewriting
                        refs/remotes/origin/* to refs/heads/*, disables
                        removing of the 'origin' remote, disables removing
                        unexported refs, disables expiring the reflog, and
                        disables the automatic post-filter gc. Also, this
                        modifies --tag-rename and --refname-callback options
                        such that instead of replacing old refs with new
                        refnames, it will instead create new refs and keep the
                        old ones around. Use with caution.
  --no-gc               Do not run 'git gc' after filtering.
  --refs REFS [REFS ...]
                        Limit history rewriting to the specified refs. Implies
                        --partial. In addition to the normal caveats of
                        --partial (mixing old and new history, no automatic
                        remapping of refs/remotes/origin/* to refs/heads/*,
                        etc.), this also may cause problems for pruning of
                        degenerate empty merge commits when negative revisions
                        are specified.
  --dry-run             Do not change the repository. Run `git fast-export`
                        and filter its output, and save both the original and
                        the filtered version for comparison. This also
                        disables rewriting commit messages due to not knowing
                        new commit IDs and disables filtering of some empty
                        commits due to inability to query the fast-import
                        backend.
  --debug               Print additional information about operations being
                        performed and commands being run. When used together
                        with --dry-run, also show extra information about what
                        would be run.
  --stdin               Instead of running `git fast-export` and filtering its
                        output, filter the fast-export stream from stdin. The
                        stdin must be in the expected input format (e.g. it
                        needs to include original-oid directives).
  --quiet               Pass --quiet to other git commands called

CALLBACKS

    Most callback functions are of the same general format.  For a command line
    argument like
      --foo-callback 'BODY'

    the following code will be compiled and called:
      def foo_callback(foo):
        BODY

    The exception on callbacks is the --file-info-callback, which will be
    discussed further below.

    Given the callback style, we can thus make a simple callback to replace
    'Jon' with 'John' in author/committer/tagger names:
      git filter-repo --name-callback 'return name.replace(b"Jon", b"John")'

    To remove all 'Tested-by' tags in commit (or tag) messages:
      git filter-repo --message-callback 'return re.sub(br"\nTested-by:.*", "", message)'

    To remove all .DS_Store files:
      git filter-repo --filename-callback 'return None if os.path.basename(filename) == b".DS_Store" else filename'

    Note that if BODY resolves to a filename, then the contents of that file
    will be used as the BODY in the callback function.

    The --file-info-callback has a more involved function callback; for it the
    following code will be compiled and called:
      def file_info_callback(filename, mode, blob_id, value):
        BODY

    It is designed to be used in cases where filtering depends on both
    filename and contents (and maybe mode).  It is called for file changes
    other than deletions (since deletions have no file contents to operate
    on).  This callback is expected to return a tuple of (filename, mode,
    blob_id).  It can make use of the following functions from the value
    instance:
      value.get_contents_by_identifier(blob_id) -> contents (bytestring)
      value.get_size_by_identifier(blob_id) -> size_of_blob (int)
      value.insert_file_with_contents(contents) -> blob_id
      value.is_binary(contents) -> bool
      value.apply_replace_text(contents) -> new_contents (bytestring)
    and can read/write the following data member from the value instance:
      value.data (dict)

    The filename can be used for renaming the file similar to
    --filename-callback (or None to drop the change), and mode is one
    of b'100644', b'100755', b'120000', or b'160000'.

    For more detailed examples and explanations AND caveats, see
      https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/newren/git-filter-repo/blob/docs/html/git-filter-repo.html#CALLBACKS

EXAMPLES

    To get a bunch of reports mentioning renames that have occurred in
    your repo and listing sizes of objects aggregated by any of path,
    directory, extension, or blob-id:
      git filter-repo --analyze

    (These reports can help you choose how to filter your repo; it can
    be useful to re-run this command after filtering to regenerate the
    report and verify the changes look correct.)

    To extract the history that touched just 'guides' and 'tools/releases':
      git filter-repo --path guides/ --path tools/releases

    To remove foo.zip and bar/baz/zips from every revision in history:
      git filter-repo --path foo.zip --path bar/baz/zips/ --invert-paths

    To replace the text 'password' with 'p455w0rd':
      git filter-repo --replace-text <(echo "password==>p455w0rd")

    To use the current version of the .mailmap file to update authors,
    committers, and taggers throughout history and make it permanent:
      git filter-repo --use-mailmap

    To extract the history of 'src/', rename all files to have a new leading
    directory 'my-module' (e.g. src/foo.java -> my-module/src/foo.java), and
    add a 'my-module-' prefix to all tags:
      git filter-repo --path src/ --to-subdirectory-filter my-module --tag-rename '':'my-module-'

    For more detailed examples and explanations, see
      https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/newren/git-filter-repo/blob/docs/html/git-filter-repo.html#EXAMPLES
